Curriculum Vita

Sunbeom So (소순범)

- Assistant Professor at GIST (Gwangju Institute of Science and Technology)
- Email: sunbeomso@gist.ac.kr
- Webpage: https://sites.google.com/site/sunbeomsoprl

Research Interests

I am interested in various research topics for improving the safety and reliability of software, including:

- Sotfware verification for automatically proving the absence of bugs in programs.
- **Software testing** for automatically finding bugs in programs.
- Software repair for automatically fixing bugs in programs.
- Software synthesis for automatically generating safe and correct programs.

To tackle my research problems, I often develop and use techniques based on *SMT-based formal* methods such as symbolic execution, but I am also interested in using other techniques such as fuzzing to effectively achieve the goal of my research.

Education

• Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering Korea University	2016.09 – 2022.08 Seoul, Korea
Thesis: Automatic Verification, Testing, and Repair of Smart Contracts Advisor: Hakjoo Oh	
• B.S. in Computer and Communication Engineering Korea University Graduation with Top Honors (Valedictorian)	2011.03 – 2016.08 Seoul, Korea

Work Experience

• Assistant Professor	2023.09 - current
School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science	Gwangju, Korea
GIST	
• Research Professor	2022.09 - 2023.08
	2022.09 - 2023.08
BK21 FOUR R&E Center for Computer Science and Engineering	Seoul, Korea
Korea University	

Publications

I have published papers at top-tier conferences in the field of software security (Security 2021, S&P 2020), software engineering (ICSE 2023, FSE 2023), programming languages (OOPSLA 2018), and artificial intelligence (IJCAI 2018).

1. SMARTFIX: Fixing Vulnerable Smart Contracts by Accelerating Generate-and-Verify Repair using Statistical Models

Sunbeom So, and Hakjoo Oh

ESEC/FSE 2023: ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering

2. DIVER: Oracle-Guided SMT Solver Testing with Unrestricted Random Mutations Jongwook Kim*, <u>Sunbeom So</u>*, and Hakjoo Oh (*: co-first authors)

ICSE 2023: 45th International Conference on Software Engineering

3. SMARTEST: Effectively Hunting Vulnerable Transaction Sequences in Smart Contracts through Language Model-Guided Symbolic Execution

Sunbeom So, Seongjoon Hong, and Hakjoo Oh

Security 2021: 30th USENIX Security Symposium

4. VERISMART: A Highly Precise Safety Verifier for Ethereum Smart Contracts Sunbeom So, Myungho Lee, Jisu Park, Heejo Lee, and Hakjoo Oh S&P 2020: 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy

5. Automatic Diagnosis and Correction of Logical Errors for Functional Programming Assignments Junho Lee, Dowon Song, <u>Sunbeom So</u>, and Hakjoo Oh

OOPSLA 2018: ACM Conference on Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages, and Applications

6. Synthesizing Pattern Programs from Examples

Sunbeom So, and Hakjoo Oh

IJCAI 2018: International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence

7. Synthesizing Imperative Programs from Examples Guided by Static Analysis Sunbeom So, and Hakjoo Oh

SAS 2017: Static Analysis Symposium

8. Synthesizing Regular Expressions from Examples for Introductory Automata Assignments Mina Lee*, <u>Sunbeom So</u>*, and Hakjoo Oh (*: co-first authors)

GPCE 2016: ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Generative Programming: Concepts and Experiences

Best Paper Award

Academic Activities

Artifact Evaluation Committee (AEC) member

- CAV 2023: 35th International Conference on Computer Aided Verification
- OOPSLA 2020: ACM Conference on Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages, and Applications

Journal Reviewer

- TSE: IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (2022)
- TOSEM: ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (2023)

Open-sourced Research Software

I have developed the following open-sourced software.

• Main developer of VeriSmart and Smartest

VERISMART: a formal safety verification tool for Solidity smart contracts SMARTEST: a symbolic execution tool for Solidity smart contracts https://github.com/kupl/VeriSmart-public

• Main developer of PAT

A pattern program synthesizer https://github.com/kupl/pat

• Main developer of Simpl

An imperative program synthesizer https://github.com/kupl/SimplPublic

• Developer of Alpharegex
A regular expression synthesizer
https://github.com/kupl/AlpharegexPublic

Research Grant (Principal Investigator)

• Research Subsidies for Ph.D. Candidates National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF) 20,000,000 KRW

2020.06 - 2021.05

Technology Transfer

◆ 스마트 컨트랙트 검증 장치 및 방법 (오학주, 소순범, 이명호)
 SOOHO.IO Inc.
 5,000,000 KRW

2020.09 - 2023.08

Awards

• The 27th Humantech Paper Award* (Participation Prize) Samsung Electronics *: # of awarded submissions: 116 out of 1991 (5.8%)	2021.02
• Naver Ph.D Fellowship Award Naver	2020.12
• Valedictorian at the College of Information & Communication Korea University	2017.02
• Best Paper Award ACM SIGPLAN GPCE 2016	2016.10

Scholarships

Junior Fellow-Research Grant
Korea University
 Honor Graduates Scholarship
Korea University
 Undergraduate Student Scholarship
Kwanjeong Educational Foundation
 Academic Excellence Scholarship
Korea University
 2017 Spring – 2020 Spring
 2015 Spring – 2016 Spring
 Academic Excellence Scholarship
Korea University

Invited Talks

SMARTEST: Effectively Hunting Vulnerable Transaction Sequences in Smart Contracts through Language Model-Guided Symbolic Execution
 Top Conference Session at Korea Software Congress (KSC) 2021
 2021.12.22

 VERISMART: A Highly Precise Safety Verifier for Ethereum Smart Contracts
 Top Conference Session at Korea Computer Congress (KCC) 2020, Online
 2020.07.03

Conference Presentations

• Synthesizing Regular Expressions from Examples for Introductory Automata Assignments GPCE 2016, Amsterdam (Netherlands) 2016.10.31